

Berlin, Germany

🛘 (+49) 174 6297908 | 🗷 morais.rm@gmail.com | 🎁 rodrigo-morais.github.io | 🖸 rodrigo-morais | 🛅 rodrigo-morais

About me_

I am looking to transition into a Data Engineering focused role, following more than two decades as a Senior Software Engineer. I've always had a strong Data focus throughout my entire career, and now that these roles have become more delineated, I'd like to dedicate myself more fully to Data Science topics.

Front-end D3.js, React, Redux, AngularJS, Elm, HTML5, CSS

Back-end REST APIs, Domain Driven Design, Ruby on Rails, NET, AWS Lambda

Databases relational and non-relational databases, Data Warehousing, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Event Sourcing

DevOps AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, CI/CD, Micro services, A/B testing, distributed systems architecture, Infrastructure as Code

Programming Javascript, Python, R, Ruby, NodeJS, Clojure, C#, Java, Haskell

Languages English, Spanish, Portuguese, German

Experience

Data Science Student Berlin, Germany

ALGO TRADING (SABBATICAL) May 2020 - current

· Built trading automations for the Brazilian stock market. Developed financial algorithms for trading stocks. Completed Data Science courses on Udemy and Coursera to deepen my knowledge of Statistics, Probability and Linear Algebra. I'm also learning R, ETL, and Python, more specifically Pandas, NumPy and Quants.

Senior Software Engineer (Data Migration)

remote

TRADESHIFT January 2019 - May 2020

- Built a pipeline for data migration from monoliths to microservices for 10+ engineering teams company-wide. Transforming data from a monolith using Postgress to a distributed service architecture using Clojure, RabbitMQ, Docker and Terraform.
- · Lead an engineering team on extracting features from monoliths to new microservices based on Java/Spring using Domain Driven Design.
- Maintained applications based on React and AngularJS.

Senior Fullstack Software Developer

Berlin, Germany

RARREI

November 2016 - January 2019

- Developed new language-learning features fullstack by building SPAs based on React, Redux, and AWS Lambda.
- · Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Terraform, TravisCI, and several AWS stacks, including API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM.
- Migrated features from vanilla Javascript applications to new moduluar stacks based on SPAs with React and Redux.
- Maintained and modularised Ruby on Rails applications.

Senior Fullstack Developer

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

April 2014 - September 2015

THOUGHTWORKS

September 2015 - November 2016

- · Supported companies to transition from monoliths to micro services. Projects include: Gap and LATAM.
- · Developed RESTful APIs using Ruby on Rails and SPAs using React and Javascript. Created CI/CD pipelines using Docker and DevOps practises and principles.
- · Consulted clients to improve their software development practices using using agile methodology and the best techniques and state of the art technologies.

Tech Lead & Senior Software Developer

remote

ITS4 COMPANY

Scopus IT

- Led the web development team. Normalisation of non-normalised SQL databases. Built data visualizations for reporting using D3.js.
- Built a social network for schools, where teachers, parents, and students could communicate in an efficient manner. I built it using C#, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, ASP.NET, NodeJS, ASP.NET MVC 5, AngularJS, Ember, SQL Server 2008, MongoDB, and Redis.

Tech Lead & Senior Software Engineer

remote 2009 - 2014

- · Led an engineering team composed of six developers.
- Developed software for Bradesco, one of the biggest banks in Brazil.
- Built Web and native Windows applications fullstack based on NET, Java, Javascript, SQL Server, HTML 5, and CSS 3.

Senior Software Developer remote

CWI SOFTWARE 2008 - 2009

Database administration of Sql server and Oracle databases. Data migration and transformation from in-house applications to SAP ERP.

Developed new features fullstack, built SPAs and RESTful APIs based on NET, Javascript, CSS, SAP, SQL Server and C#.

Tech Lead & Senior Software Developer

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil 2005 - 2008

DBC COMPANY

· Led an engineering team of five developers. Built business intelligence tools for extracting and transforming data. Created dashboards for reporting.

- Built RESTful APIs using NET and Java. Natively developed Windows applications. Built data warehousing sing Microsoft SQL server and Oracle.
- Developed software to support, control, and manage the production of steel.
- · Built new software, maintainance of legacy systems using C#, NET, SAP, Javascript, HTML, and CSS.

Software Developer Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

JOB SERVICOS DE INFORMATICA LTDA

BARRICHELLO INFORMATICA LTDA

1999 - 2005

1998 - 1999

1997 - 1998

• Developed an ERP for civil engineering and a service system for Pizza Hut using VB 6, Javascript and C#.

Software Developer Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Developed new systems and websites. Created new database models, performed data transformation and data cleaning.

Projects include: Piggato Transportaion System and internal websites using VB 6 and Javascript.

Software Developer Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

· Developed websites for labratories.

ADVN Informatica LTDA

Education

M.Sc. Software Engineering

São Paulo, Brazil

UNIBTA - Instituto Brasileiro de Tecnologia Avançada

2010

Service-oriented Architecture

B.Sc. Applied Mathmatics

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

ULBRA - Universidade Luterana do Brasil

2008

Applied Mathmatics for Computer Science